

Saurabh K. Joshi Harsh Platinum -1, B/h Anuradha Society, Ghuma, Ahmedabad 380058 Gujarat



saurabhkjoshi@yahoo.co.in



9586854636

# **PROFILE**

Serving as an HR & Admin. Manager of an IT Company along with handling Legal department. Working for a Group of NGO and previously served as a Company Secretary of that NGO Group. Handling responsibility of coordination between Board of Trustees and Advocate for various Legal documentation, compliances, Legal drafting and Trust Board Management. Preparation for Board and Annual General Meeting of Trust, its compliance and incidental matters thereto for that NGO Group.

# **EDUCATION**

High School, Commerce Higher Secondary: H. L. Gandhi Vidhyavihar School, Rajkot Done in Commerce Stream Gujarat Secondary and Higher Secondary Education Board Gujarat	Completed, April 2004 60.50 %
BBA - Bachelor of Business Administration, Management Saurashtra University Rajkot, Gujarat	Completed, April 2008 62.50 %
CS-Company Secretary Executive Programme Institute of Company Secretaries of India Delhi	Completed, December 2010 51%
CS-Company Secretary Professional Programme Group 4, Institute of Company Secretaries of India Delhi	Completed, June 2012 50%
CS-Company Secretary Professional Programme Group 1, Institute of Company Secretaries of India Delhi	Completed, December 2013 58%
CS-Company Secretary Professional Programme Group 2, Institute of Company Secretaries of India Delhi	Completed, June 2016 50%
<b>Diploma in Yoga 2018-'19</b> Somnath Sanskrit University, Veraval through affiliated center in Rajkot	Completed, October 2019 60.50 %
CS-Company Secretary Professional Programme, Pursuing Group 3 - 3 Papers to be cleared in CS Final Stage Institute of Company Secretaries of India Delhi	

### **INTERNSHIP TRAINING DETAILS**

Trainer Name: M/S Umesh Ved and Associates (Company Secretaries) Ahmedabad

**Intern Position:** Company Secretaries - CS Apprenticeship Trainee

**Training Period:** From June 2011 to October 2012

### TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Institute of Company Secretaries of India- Aptech IT Certification Programme, Institute of Company Secretaries of India Aptech, 2010
- ➤ Institute of Company Secretaries of India SIP, EDP, PDP Programmes, Institute of Company Secretaries of India, 2013
- ➤ Government recognized CCC Certificate of Computer proficiency
- Participation in regional level examinations of Sanskrit, Mathematics and NCC event at school level

## **COMPETENCIES & SKILLS:**

- Self-confidence and direction
- Eager to learn new things
- Capable to take responsibility
- Convincing power
- Excellent Written Communication skills

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### August 2022 - till date

Serving as an HR & Administration Manager, handling Legal Department of Sanskar Technolab Private Limited at Privilon - <u>Ahmedabad</u> and Legal & Secretarial functions for Shri Pushtisanskar Sansthan Trust and Group of total 7 Trusts of Junagadh.

Type of Work includes:

Apart from following responsibilities on which I am working for Sanskar Technolab Private Limited, there are tasks in next para, I am continue to work on, without holding official position for Group of NGOs:

- > Handling HR Department along with a HR team member looking after exclusively recruitment process
- ➤ Working with Accounts department for EPFO-PF and Professional Tax matters
- > Handling HR of IT team of 21 employees divided in 2 teams in different cities Ahmedabad & Junagadh
- > Enrollment, Appointment, Attendance, regular HR functions of both the teams
- Attendance and Salary Calculation for handing over final amount to Accounts department for disbursement and related banking processes
- > Documentation for HR preparation of all types of HR documents letters and HR policies etc.
- Working for digitalization of HR functions in ERP System along with software developers
- > Admin tasks of Ahmedabad Office
- Admin: Looking after to keep office premises clean, presentable and organized
- Legal: Review of legal agreements and dealing with client or developer for discussion, Documentation for Legal department
- ➤ Legal: Handling Legal functions of IT Co. related to verification of legal agreement etc. to name a few

July 2020 – July 2022 - 2 years and a month – 25 Months – PERFORMING SIMILAR TASKS WITHOUT BEING OFFICIALLY HOLDING THE POSITION. Started from Junagadh, working at Ahmedabad office since September 2021

Served as a Company Secretary at Shri Pushtisanskar Sansthan Trust and Group of 7 Trusts, Moti Haveli, Junagadh

## Type of Work includes:

- Management of Trust Board Meeting and Annual General Meetings
- Drafting of Minutes, resolution and related letters
- Coordination in Trademark Registration Process with Advocate
- Coordination between Board of Trustees and Advocate for various Legal Agreement drafting
- > Some work related to HR and employees record management
- Record keeping and provision of legal documents of Trusts for various purposes etc.
- Works related to FCRA and other NGO related regulations

## July 2015 - October 2018 - 3 Years and above 2.5 Months

# Served as Executive Assistant to Executive Trustee M/S Saurashtra Medical & Educational Charitable Trust (Project 'Life'-NGO) Rajkot Gujarat

## Type of Work includes:

- Management of Trust Board Meeting and Annual General Meetings
- Drafting of Minutes, resolution and related letters
- Coordination with Central Government Ministries and State Government, related to matters incidental to NGO - Like FCRA, SIRO registration etc.
- Coordination with bank and Auditors
- Coordination in International Charity Registration Process
- Coordination in Trademark Registration Process with Advocate
- Various online and offline Grant Application procedures
- Work for United Nations Global Compact Registration and coordination
- > Internet Search and procurement of details and documents
- > Translation from and in Gujarati
- Work related to innovation and capacity building of team including HR etc.

### January 2011 - February 2011 - 2 Months

Served as Audit Assistant -M/S Gilani and Associates (Chartered Accountants) Rajkot, Gujarat

Type of Work: Audit of Private Limited Company

## **COMPUTER PROFICIENCY**

- MS Word 2010
- MS Excel 2010
- MS Power Point 2010

## **LANGUAGES KNOWN**

- Gujarati
- > Hindi
- English

## **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

- > Yog
- Reading
- Watching movies
- Listening to music
- ➤ Internet Surfing

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Father's Name : Mr. Kishorchandra Joshi Marital Status: Unmarried

Birthday : April, 1987 Nationality: Indian

Gender : Male

# **DECLARATION**

I, Saurabh K. Joshi, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

\_\_\_\_\_

Saurabh K. Joshi Ahmedabad, Gujarat

2023